Hello.
Hey.
Jared says they're having lots of excitement with regulatory investigations.
Jared?
Yeah.
Get anybody fired in the last two days.
Me?
No?
Wade.
That's what we talked about last time.
That he had gotten his co-worker fired.
I didn't get him fired.
He got himself.
He felt fired.
See?
Anyway, he's not officially fired.
He's still on payroll, but he's doing nothing.
Sounds like he won.
He'll be fine.
I mean, I wouldn't say he's, yeah, he's still wasting time.
He's just not wasting my time.
No, his replacement, or you know, the guy who's picked up the Slack has been just amazing.
Like, since, you know, since he took over the week, we got our root complex completely buttoned up.
That's all working.
And now we're halfway to getting our USB endpoint working and probably be close to getting Ethernet next week and then we'll be done.
Are you in a closet?
I mean, that just sounds like a virtual background, right?
He is, isn't he?
What entertaining virtual backgrounds can we make up here?
I don't know.
What's wrong with the virtual dog in the background?
It's not like Gary's room is all that attractive.
Well, mine's not.
Yours is, well, you have a dog at least.
It's a little bit more interesting in the background.
Gary has a cat, just not in frame.
But you're like surrounded by hanging clothes.
Like it's a closet, isn't it?
It is a closet.
Looks like a very nice, spacious walk-in closet.
It's a walk-in closet.
Yeah.
I mean, what's the status?
Isn't he in a garage or something?
It sure looks like it.
Where is he?
Not in a garage.
This might be very short.
Let's see.
He'll be here.
I know.
He got.
It's going to be a short session, though.
Well, we'll just end at 10.30, like always, right?
Yeah.
There we go.
All right.
We're all here.
Let's do it.
GM.
Hello.
Okay.
Can you not hear us?
Nick is so little in that picture, Cassatas.
I know.
I just.
Yeah, it was a long time ago.
I just fixed my audio.
Can you guys see me?
Yeah, we can see you.
Excellent.
David refuses to come out of the closet.
What?
Which one of many?
The one he's in.
I'm feeling awkward here, right?
Like that this is some kind of private conversation.
Wade is amused that my computer is set up in a closet because I live in a tiny little house where there's no space.
Oh, really?
I mean, my desk is actually embedded in the closet in this room, so we gutted it and like the desk takes up the entire width of the closet.
It's really nice.
Nice.
So that's cool.
But like my favorite flex is one of my co-workers at VMware, Matt Amdur.
You may recall him, Dave.
He sat in a hallway between his laundry over here and his bedroom over here.
And there was a tiny little window.
So we're talking about a distance that's, you know, how much of a hallway is, right?
And so what he did was he put a fake bookshelf right above the window.
Oh, like just a mat painting or something?
No, just, you know, one of those teeth tiny little bookshelves.
It was like maybe like a decorative shelf.
Like a dollhouse bookshelf.
Probably if you put more than two books on it, it would be good.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
Like something really cheap, but it made it look like he was in a real office.
Oh, okay.
All right.
Well done.
He didn't have his shirts hanging up in the background.
That's good.
Good for him.
I just used the Zoom blur feature, but I had to turn it off earlier tonight because.
Yes.
Victor and I were doing a joint Zoom, and with blur on, he was blurred out.
So I forgot to turn it on again.
All right.
So we're marching back to Phandalin, I believe.
We're going to Leilon, right?
Hi, buddy.
We can rest in Phandalin.
I've got some business there.
I got a.
Well, okay, guys, you're not supposed to go to Phandalin to the Leilon now.
Well, we'll talk about that.
That's act three.
We're still in Act one.
Yes.
I like speedrunning.
We kill our drow.
We put her in a box.
We throw fire on the ground.
Did we run the last campaign?
You can speedrun this one?
No.
Don't put your drow in a box.
Oh, she's useful.
Maybe you haven't looked up shadow boxing yet because it would spoil things.
It's just a technique for speedrunning.
You put a corpse in a box on a fiery patch of ground and it completely fucks with the engine.
Did they not fix that bug?
I mean, it's been around since before.
It was since like some instances of it, but not all.
Yeah.
I think I saw the 15-minute speedrun of the whole game that used that.
Kill Shadowheart, put her in the box, throw the fire on the ground, throw the box.
Quite inventive, actually.
Speedrunners are neat.
Okay.
All right.
So I just read about that glitch.
Shadow boxing.
Yes.
I didn't realize it was literally box Shadowheart.
Yeah.
You put her in a box.
You have to kill her to put her in a box in the middle of a cutscene.
Yes.
And it teleports you to the end of Act Two.
Yep.
Where you can blow shit up with Gale.
You mean blow Gale up?
Blow shit up.
I'm not revealing anything.
Oh, wait.
You already know about Act 3.
He's fine.
Did you get to Act 3?
I'm in the middle of Act 3.
Yeah.
You know Gale's whole story.
To the Lower City.
And then the Lower City has too much going on.
That was how I felt too.
It was very overwhelming.
I actually had to stop playing for a while.
It was too overwhelming.
Oh, wow.
You don't have to finish everything.
Yeah.
You do not have to side quest infinitely.
Breath first searches.
Yeah, this is how Gary operates.
Just for the record, not every quest has to be completed.
Yeah, I was sad I didn't finish the clown.
I'm close to the clown.
I wanted to.
Really?
It's not even a useful item that you get.
It's kind of a waste.
I don't know.
It was at the end of it.
I wanted to finish it, but I missed one or two body parts.
Yeah, it doesn't really make sense that somehow the clown ended up in all those different places behind locked doors and ancient things.
Are we really having a conversation?
I just want to make sure that we're...
The clown is here.
I think we're talking about Orin.
So yes.
Yes, Orin.
We're talking about the...
We're talking about a fantasy game in which a deadly assassin can materialize out of nothing wearing any costume she wants.
And we're discussing whether said deadly assassin who's drenched in blood could drop body parts wherever she wants.
I just want to make sure that's what we're talking about.
Yeah.
Yes.
Talking about.
Okay.
Just double checking.
Got it.
Okay.
So first of all, so first of all, there's the quest that what's his name has?
Well, what's his name?
You can go back to Phandalin and do some research.
Hold on.
I'm just saying it's on your way.
That's why.
Oh, we're doing a quest on the way?
I just wanted to point out that it was on the way.
What's on the way?
Oh, on the way, not underway.
Okay.
No, no, on the way.
Yeah, yeah.
What's on the way?
I guess I didn't realize there was something on the way.
Well, so what's her name?
Adabra.
The girl we had to bring home, the naturalist.
The naturalist.
The nudist, whatever.
She's the one that was in the house that we rescued.
Yeah.
The one who didn't want to leave.
Is this written on the quest tracker?
It should have been.
It's not.
It's definitely a quest.
As you guys were leaving Phandalin, she approached Soma and gave you guys a quest.
I mean, I remember some of the discussion.
I do not appear to see it on the questions.
There was escort Adabra and Jarek to Phandalin after an orc attack, which we did.
Yeah, okay.
Well, let me just remind you what the quest was.
All right, because I don't see it on the tracker.
Yeah, we've failed our bookkeeping.
I'm like disappointed in you guys.
I've disappointed us too.
I feel pretty good about the quests.
Yeah, I know.
You keep occasionally.
What?
Occasionally, use a critical failure on our bookkeeping skill.
Keep you on your toes.
All right, where was this?
Is this Mountain Toad's Gold Mine?
No, no, no, no.
Okay.
All right.
Where was it?
I need to go find it.
So.
Actually, Leylon is kind of on the way back.
Yeah, we should just stop.
It's not that far off.
Okay, we do what we want.
Could, I don't know, it'd be interesting to go to a different town.
Never winter is pretty far.
All right.
Okay.
Yes.
So basically, Soma, what's her name?
Sorry.
So let me go.
Adabra Boda.
Adabra.
Abracadabra.
Okay.
She remarked how there was an old grove that was just past the Whisper Road.
So I'll just mark it here.
So I'll just put you guys on the world map so you know what I'm talking about.
You guys hear it?
That sounds the whisper woods.
Whisper woods.
Yes.
Okay.
There's that path in there or something.
No, no, it's not.
It was so vibrant, a testament to Chauntea's blessing, deeming with life, but now it is dying.
Not naturally, mind you.
This isn't the slow dance of seasons, nor the honest bite of winter.
She says, there is a strange magical blight spreading through it.
The trees twist in the natural waves, their leaves too bright or too sickly pale, as if almost as if the colors are wrong.
And she then concludes, I have observed these dreadful signs, and I fear that folks, that something is behind it, whether it's the interventionists or something else, their constant meddling, their zealous rituals, and forceful cleansing around Phandalin and Leilon.
So I did not put that out of curse.
We're good at lifting curses.
Yeah, because curse involves killing stuff.
What?
Like the cursebusters.
How much money was involved in saving the Whispering Wood?
It's not about the money.
It's about keeping the forests in check.
Dude, like the forest is not going to build my music studio.
And apparently, most of the treasure that we're treasure that we're getting, I can't even use to build the music studio.
So yes, I want to know how much they're going to pay me to solve the goddamn curse in the house.
Dabra did not make any monetary offer.
It's going to be hard to get Vukerden in on this one.
Phandalin.
Okay.
So you're not doing the quest.
Not on this trip.
Yeah, I guess not.
It's a little out of the way.
Sure, we'll get closer to it later.
Actually, I don't see it on the map.
Where is it?
It's north of Phandalin.
It's the red.
It's on your way.
It's literally on your way.
Like, you literally are going to come down the road and you're just going to take two legs of a triangle on our way.
Yeah, we're headed east.
Yeah.
The Whispering Woods are north east.
And Phandalin.
Oh, I see them now.
Whispering Woods.
It's like, is this the same we had been hearing that the Neverwinter Wood?
That there was something this is different than we keep hearing that strange magic pervades Neverwinter wood.
You've heard about that too.
These are unrelated.
Separate separate issue.
Okay.
Yes.
And Dabra will be.
Maybe if we talk to the guild master in town or the mayor or whatever his name is about the Whispering Woods, he'll have some more information.
Who is Adabra anyway?
We don't really know who she is.
She was the daughter of some noble, wasn't she?
Adabra was the woman who was at Umbrage Hill, who was the lady who you rescued from the town and gave you extra money for helping and convinced what's his name to give you extra money.
Oh, oh, that's Adabra.
Oh, okay.
Adabra is the one that we is the yes, is the old lady who you love.
Right.
And so she was kind of hoping that, you know, one good turn would lead to another, but clearly that I see.
Vukerden is not motivated by good turns.
She's a midwife.
Yes.
She's the midwife.
Yeah.
So she's like, yeah, among many others, she's also an herbalist.
But she and I had a connection when we told her she understood what I was trying to do, and that I needed organic fair trade gold.
Yeah.
Yes, she offered me nothing.
No, but then what happened was you decided to go work for the Order of the Gauntlet and she stopped talking to you and talked to Soma.
Yeah.
She's got Soma's ear.
I'm not so sure about the Order of the Gauntlet after that random attack that seemed like they knew exactly where we were going.
So she's not telling me Adabra is not a fan of the Order of the Gauntlet.
What you know is that you have to roll your.
Yes, you know that she, after you started wearing your pin, she became a lot less interested in you and only spoke to Soma.
In fact, she spoke to Soma privately.
Well, maybe this is why I don't remember this conversation at all.
Yes, I know.
It doesn't matter.
Maybe that's why it's not on the quest tracker.
It was probably on me to write it down.
Yeah, anyway.
Okay.
Yeah, that's my bad.
The pin is gone.
I don't know about this quest.
So as far as I'm concerned, we're going to Phandalin.
Okay.
The rest of you want to go?
Sure.
To Phandalin.
Yeah.
Soma's not going to make waves.
All right.
To Phandalin it is.
She guides people where they want to go.
You know, guiding tour guide whatever.
All right.
You arrive in Phandalin.
Sorry.
I did not change it.
It has not changed.
All right.
You are in Phandalin.
Okay.
Do we need to go back to the mayor and talk with him about the Blighthouse?
Yes.
All right.
So you.
The Town Master.
Is that his name?
Yes.
Town Master.
The guy who always has a locked door.
Yes.
Assumes we're dragons.
Do we have like a secret knock for them yet?
I'm going to put his name there so we have it.
All right.
So you arrive at Harbin's.
You arrive at the Phandalin.
While you're there, let's get her out.
Adabra sees you and approaches the four of you.
And we'll give Harbin an icon as well.
Harbin an icon so that we have all the characters on the board.
So, Adabra sees, notices you coming into town.
It's a small town.
And she steps out and asks, asks to ask Soma, so did you visit the Whispering Wood?
No, we haven't quite made it into our journeys yet.
She goes, well, she looks at you a little bit curious.
She goes, why not?
It's a little out of the way while we were out clearing out other blights on the land.
Oh, okay.
Well, she goes, I see.
I see.
There's a lot of it going around.
She then looks at you and says, this is important.
This is important work, Soma.
If we let these changes happen, the balance, the natural balance will be disturbed.
She then goes, please, please take care of this.
And then she walks away.
Oh, Adabra, before you walk away.
Yes.
Can I talk to you about something?
She looks at you, of course.
What would you need?
A token of good health?
Is there a woman in a family way that needs to be taken care of?
Midwife.
Do you know anything about the Order of the Gauntlet?
Do I know about the Order of the Gauntlet?
Yes, I know many things about the Order.
She goes, she looks at you, goes, why would you want to know?
She then notices you don't have a pen, whatever happened to your pin.
It was broken in a battle.
Oh, we're not.
I thought you were using that as planted evidence.
No.
Okay.
It was lost in the battle.
Sounds like a cat found a toy.
The cat comes into the room, closes the door, and then Cat reopened the door.
And so she has realized that if she plays with the doorstop, then it summons the human to open the door for her.
Smart cat.
So Adabra looks at you and goes, Well, I think they're a fine organization.
Why do you ask?
I just don't know very much about them.
What's there to know?
They seem very mysterious.
Oh, they're not mysterious.
They're quite transparent.
Really?
Oh, yes.
Where can I learn more about this transparent organization?
Well, it's quite transparent what they want.
Their view is that the world could be made better.
They want to make the world better.
They seem to think that the world is in imbalance and that by making it better, things will get better.
Ah.
Instead of recognizing that the world is fine just the way it is and that in their attempts to make things better, they make things worse.
Theirs is an ideology of change for the better.
What happens when you change it for the better?
Why, do things get better?
No, the worse things get more powerful and more dangerous.
The more you push along one road, the worse it gets along another.
They are committed.
They are committed to the foolish path of imbalance.
You don't suppose they're the ones messing with the Whispering Woods.
She goes, hmm, the Whispering Woods.
She goes, the Whispering Woods.
I would be.
No, no, the Whispering Woods is not.
I do not believe it is caused by the Whispering Woods.
I believe it is caused as a result of the interventionists meddling in affairs they should not be.
Would have been a nice angle.
She goes, oh, the order of the lords, sorry, the order of the gauntlet.
They're too busy chasing dragons and killing orcs and trying to clear the land for civilization, slaughtering monsters.
At least with normal adventures, they slaughter a monster and take its treasures.
These ones slaughter a monster and move on or donate it to some charity in which they again tried to do good.
They're always shameful.
I mean, like all that good, good treasure.
She's really committed to neutrality.
Really committed.
So beautiful, yet so neutral.
She's like, there's a path of madness.
Madness.
Yes.
Is it not mad to not see that the universe itself, the multiverse itself, is one thing?
But there isn't good and there isn't evil.
There's just the thing.
And that she is, and that the order of the gauntlet is committed to its path.
Soma understands this.
And I thought you did.
Soma, you understand that there's neither good nor evil?
I understand that all things are, you know, temporary.
I did not say there's no such thing as a good act or an evil act, but the idea that by striving, one can force the world to be better, good or evil.
Well, one can do that, but what happens is that the evil will then have to respond.
And it won't respond gently.
It will respond with full force.
The more you push in one direction, the bigger the reaction in the other direction is.
And isn't our goal to maintain the symbiosis of the multiverse?
Instead, what happens is the worlds fall apart.
Maybe we really should have left you in that house.
Oh, you do not like her.
Well, I mean, why did we go save her?
Because of 52 act.
She doesn't want to do it.
She pauses and says, my dear friend Vukradin, as you recall, I wish to be left alone in my house, but you did insist I come here.
And then when you asked for more money from Harbin, did I not intervene to get you more money?
You did.
Yes.
And why did I do this?
Because I don't know.
Why did you do it?
Because it's not about good or evil.
It's about seeing balance.
And I saw the balance of your just cause.
You are devoted to music.
You are not devoted to changing evil or changing harm.
Music is part of the music of the universe.
You are not a devotee of the powers of good or even the devotee of the powers of evil.
So I thought, as someone who was so passionate about music, that you would see the world as Soma and I do.
Instead, I notice by your choice of alliances that you see things very differently than me.
Okay, I'm done talking to her.
She's being patronizing.
See ya.
She goes, very well.
I hope you'll take care of the issues of the Whispering Woods.
Otherwise, things will get worse.
I'll work on him.
I don't know.
Maybe we shouldn't disturb the natural order.
Natural order is actively being disturbed.
Exactly, says Adabra.
It is actively being disturbed.
I'd at least like to know who's doing it when we get a chance.
So, all right.
So, Adabra looks at you and says, Could I sell you any potions of healing?
I think we're all right.
Well, then, if you need anything from me, I will just be over here.
All right.
Okay.
So, where else do you want to go?
Do we have any treasure to sell?
There's some octopus hide armor, right?
I think I would like to invest.
I would like to talk to some shopkeepers about all of this blood loot we found.
And is there a way to identify, are there like markings on it that would indicate where it came from?
Or maybe we should, are there any markings that indicate any sort of points of origin or anything like that that could be helpful?
I mean, they all turn to you and say, that's what identify spells are for.
Okay, some of those.
She go, do you need to go find a magic user for one of those?
Can we just get some scrolls?
And Lionshield Coster says, well, I don't happen to have some identify scrolls today, but if you give me a few days, I could probably dig some up or at least find you a bead on someone who could do it or find you the name of a magic user who could help.
Probably we're going to need a magic user who's willing to do this pro bono.
I don't know if you have to pay a lot of money for identify spells.
Or, you know, you could go talk to your friend, the Sir Kaelen, the Sir Kaelen who betrayed me?
I don't know.
I'm not a big deal with him right now.
Do you know whether he betrayed you?
I suspect that he did.
You don't want to confront him about it?
Well, he's not here, right?
Didn't he leave town?
No, no, he stayed in town.
He said town.
Yeah.
Corbin just multi-class into a wizard.
Who did?
We should have Corbin multi-class into a wizard.
Corbin.
Yeah, so he can do our identify spells.
Yes.
He's a lackey that hangs out at camp and casts buff spells on us.
That's right.
Don't underestimate his contribution.
Do not underestimate his contribution.
All right.
Okay.
So where would you like to go?
Would you like to go to the tavern?
Was there any sort of.
Was there anyone?
Who gave us the quest for the Tower of Storms?
Nobody gave you the quest for the Tower of Storms.
You heard a rumor and you followed it.
Okay.
That doesn't sound like us.
Well,
it does seem like you should still tell the town keeper because he will need to see if he wants to keep the lighthouse stocked.
That's a good point.
Yeah, keep the fire going, maybe appoint a new master of the lighthouse to take care of it.
They need to hire a light keeper.
We do.
Glorious lightkeeper.
All right.
That's a good idea.
So to Harbin Wester, to Harbin.
He's like, Harbin, Harbin sees you guys and is like, well, what a wonderful surprise to see you all.
Yeah.
Talos?
Did you realize there was an infestation of Talos on the coast?
He looks at you funny.
We have dragons and now we have Talos.
Yeah.
Oh, that's quite awful.
That is very awful.
But we did sanctify the altar.
No more Talos.
We did?
Yes.
Oh, excellent.
And so there's no more Talos.
Yeah, no more Talos.
Well, no, but we need to go investigate in Leilon.
There's more going on there.
Well, not at the Lighthouse.
Yeah, the Lighthouse is good, but Leilon, the Talos worship may continue.
But there's no one working the Lighthouse, so the light will eventually go out.
And light is important.
Harbin goes, I think Lord Neverwinter will be delighted to find out that you have managed to cleanse the lighthouse of the evildoers who had taken ownership of it.
And I will make sure to send him a note.
Thank you.
Make sure you put in a good word for us.
I will absolutely put in a great.
Could we go up to Neverwinter and take it to him personally?
You could, I suppose.
I don't know whether he'd want to see you, but he's a very busy man.
If this is something you wish to do, far be it for me to say anything.
I mean, there are problems within the town, and you did sign up to come and help here.
And if you're going back to Lord of Neverwinter while the town is still in a state of disrepair, it's not quite clear how he'll react.
But far be it for me to tell you what to do.
Okay.
I mean, he's a lord of a large city.
You're a third-level character.
We're not very, we're not very, we don't raid.
And we did agree to come here.
And yes, and so that's that's a good point.
Yes.
So, I mean, he's like, you could go there and you'll just send you back.
Or, or worse, like with like withdraw your tax-free status and send you back.
All right, maybe we should go talk to Sir Kaelen.
All right.
Let me just do something here.
Like something I need to do here
to just find something.
Give me one second.
All right.
Okay.
Okie dokie.
All right.
So you go to Sir Kaelen.
Yes.
Sir Kaelen, Sir Kaelen is sitting there and is looking really happy to see you.
Spider-Man is also looking happy to see you.
Why is he happy to see us?
Well, because, you know, Vukradin played some music that was very successful in the pub.
You know, he got to tell the story about how he got his nickname of Spider-Man.
I mean, he likes us.
He likes us.
You're good for business.
Got it.
You're working on the problems of the area.
I mean, these are all good things.
Why wouldn't?
Plus, you know, you're helping clear the area of evil agents.
Right.
So, like, from his perspective, why wouldn't he?
All right.
We're back.
Sir Kaelen is delighted to see you.
He says, he goes, I, Vukradin, how was your were you able to achieve victory in and secure the tower from its uh the evil the evil that was there baz is was there evil there remember we said there were three options it was evil oh there was talos talos he goes paul pauses and says now that is of grave concern talos was it one was it was it was was was there anything else strange about talos this cleric of talos he had a hole in his chest a little a hole in his chest yeah he had an used his he had illuminated his heart and used it to light the lighthouse he goes this is very strange a typical shaman of talos could not do such things there's some hidden force deeper here there were harpies too yeah we didn't find any greater force there that we noticed yes well there's who knows what's going on there's so many different this ever since the end of the war of the giants and the war of the dragons this whole area has been in a state of chaos many of my brethren died fighting the dragons several died fighting the barbarians sorry something happened though along the way to the to the tower that i need to ask you about he goes what we were ambushed he goes my goodness by whom
or someone who knew someone who knew we were coming uh he denies he denies it and he's telling the truth actually but who would have known that but who would have known that we were coming
I don't feel like we've been very secretive.
Yeah, so Sir Kaelen goes, Let me see.
He raises his hand.
Who knew that these individuals were willing to go to the Tower of the Storm in this bar?
People raise their head.
Somebody goes, We were taking bets on whether all four would come back or whether they would ditch the bard.
Wait, shouldn't we get a cut of those bets?
I think we're going to need to be more secretive.
Spider-Man points to a betting pool.
What are you guys betting we'll do next?
Yeah, tell us the odds and we'll, you know, right.
Can we get in on this?
We'll take a dive.
If I win, this is fair trade gold.
It's still a little shadowy gotten, you know.
So Spider-Man says, you know, Vukradin, you're a good sport.
And the betting pool was that they would kill you because they couldn't stand.
You're patronizing.
Your patronizing tone.
He actually came in handy.
Although he goes, but I want you to know that I believe that your musical inspiration would cause everyone, the team, to rally behind you.
And I want you to know I won the pool.
So he gives you 10 gold pieces.
There you go.
10 fair trade gold.
He gives you 10 gold pieces.
Okay.
He gives you 10 gold pieces and then says, but dude, I think the only person who didn't know you were going to the Tower of Storms was the dead.
I mean, the truly dead, not the partially dead or the undead or the coming back.
All right, we're going to be more secretive about.
All right.
Just to be clear, you had a big shouting match in the middle of the town.
You declared.
I don't remember doing that, but okay.
Maybe I did.
They were definitely not going.
Did I work it into the music?
No, no.
What happened was that you barged up to Harbin and said, How do I destroy a tower?
Briefly, Ranway.
We talked to Harbin about it.
Yes, but in the middle of the square, this was not a private and discreet conversation.
Okay.
All right.
I have a couple more questions for Sir Kaelen.
Yes, absolutely.
Sir Kaelen.
Do you know Adabra?
Yes.
She's a wonderful woman.
She doesn't care so much for you and your organization.
Oh, yes.
Well, there's that.
She is a member of the Emerald Gauntlet, the Emerald Enclave.
Yes, she is one of the Emerald Enclave.
And the Order of the Gauntlet and the Emerald Enclave have allied at times when great evil has faced the realms.
There's always the No, no, no, not presently.
There's no great force.
We defeated the Giants, the war with the barbarians.
Sorry, the endless wars that occurred after the defeat of the barbarians.
Sorry, keep stumbling over this.
Let's just say the end of the wars of the giants.
How about we phrase it that way?
The end of the wars of the giants.
He's trying not to offend Brubear.
No, no, no.
The last time that we agreed to work together was during the when Tiamat showed up.
Quite a while ago.
Yeah.
So Tiamat showed up.
It was a very surprising thing.
We were all very surprised when they showed up.
Everyone had said that the Order of the Gaunt, the Emerald Enclave would not arrive, but one of the heroes of the War of the Giants was able to convince one of their leaders who brought a faction of the Emerald Enclave whose treants served as a definitive force that helped us defeat the armies outside of the war, the Well of the Dragons.
And so the Emerald Enclave and the Order of the Gauntlet are friends, even though we do not always see eye to eye.
There's, we, we, and then he pauses.
They believe that there is some mythical balance that needs to be maintained.
We believe that that if you do not, if you do not strive for good, the mythical balance will crush everything that is beautiful.
And he goes off and on and on and on about his, you know, I could give you this.
His belief that there's a, you know, a better call.
Universal good.
Yes, universal good and the importance of heroism and acts of heroism.
Oh, I think, yeah.
So he says, fighting for what's right has meaning, has intrinsic meaning.
Right.
So, yeah, he's very much fighting for what's right.
Well, let's be clear, Adabra's also fighting for what she thinks is right.
She thinks she is right.
No, but she thinks there's no nothing that's truly right or truly evil.
So there's that too.
No, no, that's not true.
She believes that she believes that the evil.
She believes the balance is intrinsically good.
Right.
So I just want to declare: it's not that she doesn't believe there's any evil or good.
It's like part Jedi.
Yes.
Okay.
So, yeah, Sir Kaelen.
So yeah, Sir Kaelen is as surprised as you are about this ambush.
He goes, he does mention that there's all sorts of things, he's worried.
He does mention that he's concerned because there has been tales of bandits in the area.
Yeah, have you heard anything about the Carver?
He goes, well, I've heard that he looks at you and says, well, that's why I'm still in town.
What do you mean?
What?
He goes, well, there's a rumor of a new bandit leader who's taken up residence around here called the Carver.
Any idea where?
No.
No, that's what I was hoping.
You know, I would get an agent.
That would be you.
And we would find out where he was, and then we'd call in the cavalry.
Oh, okay.
So we just need to do some recon, and then you'll flush him out.
Well, yes, if that's what's necessary.
Interesting.
All right.
Recon mission.
He goes, but we don't have any, we don't know anything about him other than there have been organized raids.
And some of the humanoids seem to be a little bit more organized these days than normal.
What if we knew someone that had worked for him?
We just happened to have one.
Well, that would be excellent.
Would he be a high-ranking member of the group?
He'd probably be the lowest lackey imaginable.
Yeah.
No.
Pretty sure he's.
I think he's still got trainee on his armor.
I think he's told us everything he knows and he doesn't know anything.
Yeah.
So now, so Kaelen goes, one of the challenges of this Carver individual, most bandits like to brag and strut their stuff and let everybody know who they are.
And that makes them relatively straightforward to find.
You cast some clairvoyant spells and they're quickly identified.
This one seems to be a little bit cleverer than that.
He's been hiding his, he's been hiding himself.
He's been hiding himself, hiding behind a name, hiding behind the deadly acts of violence of his crew.
I wonder if he's kind of like the Dread Pirate Roberts.
And do you know anything about the Whispering Woods?
Oh, the Whispering Woods.
What do I know about the Whispering Woods?
Let me just check.
He goes.
All right.
So actually, I did make a slight mistake on his location.
I'm sorry.
I was wrong.
It's actually closer to Phandalin.
That was my mistake.
Oh, yeah.
I mean, you put it pretty far out of our.
It wasn't supposed to be that far.
So hold on.
Let me just do this.
Let me just make a map.
I'm going to just draw some lips.
It's a blue circle.
Yeah, I'm going to make it green.
Oh, that's very close.
Yeah, we're literally there.
Yeah, it's like it's right outside Phandalin.
It's like an hour's walk.
Yeah, sorry.
It was, I was like going, why is this like this seemed like wrong?
So I apologize for that.
That's okay.
Well, do you know anything about it?
Sir Kaelen?
Yeah, that's close enough that someone can just go out on her own if the party doesn't go along.
Like, it's fine.
Yeah.
All right.
So what does he know about the Whispering Woods?
Okay, let me just see.
What does he know?
Well.
He goes, the Whispering Grove was a charming little area nearby that people used to go to relax.
There was a nice little bit of trees.
It was a nice little bit of shade you could get in the hilly area around here.
It was well respected.
But something's happened over the last few, has been happening over the last few months, and people just don't go there anymore.
Can you describe this something?
He goes, to be quite honest with you, I haven't really gone there.
And Adabra has been always been saying that there's some kind of change to the world there, that there's some kind of blight.
And so I kind of ascribed it to the kind of thing, since nobody had gotten hurt, and I was dealing with higher, we were dealing with higher priority issues, I really didn't want to spend time on what felt like an internal matter of the Emerald Enclave about a bunch of trees having blight.
Not concerned that a blight will spread.
No, he's not.
Okay.
But he goes, it is what it is.
He does say he goes, the townspeople would be grateful for you if you were to go deal with it.
Ever since this blight, people haven't been going there.
Are there any mages live nearby?
Mages living nearby.
What level mage do you need?
Level is identify.
I'm working on that.
Looks like.
Oh, identify as a first-level spell.
I could probably just burn it.
You were going to say, Gary, what are you looking for?
Oh, is that the identify spell?
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, you know, if Whispering Woods is trouble and it's so close to town, then it seems like priority to me.
I do have access to identify.
There we go.
That is definitely on brand for you to have.
Yeah, that one definitely sounds like.
And I have locate object, although it seems to work in reverse.
I have mending, so I can put things back in later order.
As he's muttering, he goes, quite honestly, the thing that I don't take seriously about Soma is that she claims there's some kind of interplanar interference related to this grove.
And the most ridiculous things I've heard in my life.
We have an interplanar being right before you.
Which one?
Isn't Vukradin the half Celestial or whatever?
Well, no, no.
He goes, there's many interplanars.
This one worships a cleric.
That one worships a god.
This one worships a power.
She claims that there's some kind of peculiar, magical, planar event.
Quite honestly, I think she's gone mad.
Some of the Emerald Enclave, after the intervention against Tiamat, have declared that the demons themselves are part of the natural world.
And nobody's going to actually check it out that you've heard directly from, huh?
He goes, it's a few hours out of town.
Nobody's been bothered.
We have a dragon flying about.
You know, part of the reason Lord Neverember sent out that check for people to go find monsters was because we didn't have people to go do that.
Okay.
You guys need help.
Well, yes.
Sir Kaelen goes, yes, yes, we do.
Do you know how to acquire help?
Did you know that money helps get help?
Yes.
But the order of the gauntlet is not like the Harpers, which have resorted to hiring people to augment their ranks.
The Harpers will hire me?
Expect everyone to work for free.
Got it.
Do you know where I can contact them?
Oh, no.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Do you actually say that?
No, no, this is Wade saying that.
You know what I'm saying?
Does he actually say that?
He goes, yes, a Harper agent.
I'm sure that one will pass by this town at some point in time.
Just look for the person who's running away from the danger and taking notes of it.
And then sending me in with a pocket full of gold.
He thinks this is very funny, right?
He doesn't realize that you're being serious.
He goes, next thing you're going to tell me is you want to go work for the Zhentarim.
No.
All of their gold is stolen.
Exactly.
You should just join the Emerald Enclave where gold doesn't really mean anything.
Won't build me my music studio.
All right.
So apparently I do have an identify spell, so I can cast identify on all of these objects.
So we can get that information.
I don't know why I didn't realize that earlier.
Okay.
I thought it was higher level.
It's not like you forgot you could shoot two arrows or something.
Okay.
So this apparently is only supposed to tell you about what magic I have.
No, I read that.
Yeah.
I don't know if you want to bend the rules or if you want to do something else or if it's just not possible to get this information.
Also, technically, every cast requires a pearl worth a hundred gold pieces.
Yeah, I think, I mean, here's what I'll do.
You get the standard.
You get what it says without any magical item.
But if you want the augmented historical, do you want me to tell you why?
Because the GM then has to go.
I can burn the blood on it.
That's the TPU cost.
There's no.
I have to go into ChatGPT to start.
Give me a backstory for this item, this armor.
Somewhere there's a server burning lots of coal to give you an answer on this one, Mendenhall.
You have to pay for that coal.
That's why the data center should be nuclear powered.
There you go.
Or solar.
Or Talos powered.
I don't know.
Talus.
I'm a big fan of talus power.
All right.
Um.
So, what are you going to do?
Are you going to burn a pearl worth 100 gold pieces?
That would not be consistent with my plan to build a music studio.
I mean, morally, I would be okay with using the blood money, but that would really betray my friends here.
We didn't find any pearls at all.
I don't think I'm quite that selfish at this point.
We did find gems, but I don't think we found.
No, you did not find 100 GP pearl.
No, we did not.
So, I'm going to go with 100.
Oh, we did find six pearls of 100 GP each.
We did.
It is actually on the tracker.
Six pearls of 100 GP each.
Yeah.
That's good.
Get generating.
What are the chances, huh?
I still, I'm starting to feel the conflict of betraying my friend.
All right.
Well, you don't have to make a decision now, remember?
Okay.
And you could also ask what's his name whether he could help you get that information.
For Kalen?
Yes.
Yeah, I could ask him.
Yeah, we found all of this treasure.
Well, do you tell him about the boats and the names of the boats?
Yeah, sure.
Yeah.
I don't remember the names.
I wasn't sure I trusted him enough, but you're going to tell him.
All right.
So he says that's all very interesting.
I will have to take some notes and ask around.
Come back in a few days, and maybe I will have something for you.
And he pauses and says it's a good thing that we have people like you who are concerned with returning the stolen goods to their rightful owners instead of taking them as if the dead are to be robbed.
Yeah.
And we'll have to make sure that they know what the secret code was on the inside of the chest.
What'd you say?
I want to make sure they know what the secret code was on the inside of the chest.
Yes.
What?
He looks at you.
What's the secret code?
There's a secret code on the inside of the chest.
Yeah.
He's making shit up.
I'm trying to throw him off.
Yeah.
All right.
Should we just leave town without saying anything?
Or should we purposely tell people we're going somewhere else?
Hold on.
So there's also the small matter of, you know, you're going to have to spend the night because it's kind of like.
Yeah.
It's been a journey.
Yeah, that's fine.
Give it the whisper once in the at night.
No.
Sleep sounds good.
Yeah.
Let's play some music.
Play some music.
Bruberi will be entertained.
Let's see how it goes.
Feeling good.
Yeah.
That's not too shabby.
We're rocking tonight.
I should make some money.
That was such a good performance.
I should get some gold pieces thrown at me.
Or at least silver.
Making it hail.
Making it rain.
Two silver pieces.
I rolled the d2.
Oh, yeah.
I rolled the d20.
I was like, okay, one to 20 silver pieces.
I'll take them.
It's harder.
And we no longer have to pay for the room, so that's nice.
Are we all playing together?
Sure, you guys can jam with me.
I mean, let's be clear.
Well, if Valfine is dancing with you, remember, she balances out your complex music with her drows skills.
So that increases the payload.
She's more of a pop number.
No, no, no.
What happens is that as a result, the music is enjoyed by more people, right?
Yeah, exactly.
Brukridin plays a very subtle kind of music that doesn't appeal to the masses, which is why.
Yeah, so I found.
Right.
So he only gets one D20.
But when he plays with Valfine, he gets two D20s worth of stuff.
Cool.
What'd we get?
Bruperi and Valfin both got 14s.
No, I'm rolling the.
Oh, you rolled 14s.
Okay, yeah.
So you've got another eight silver pieces.
Wow.
All right.
That's like the equivalent of a whole gold piece.
Yeah, so there's like moved it up in the ranks.
Did you add the money already?
I did, yeah.
Okay.
Ten silvers.
Territory.
All right.
So is it morning?
Hold on.
Is the town ransacked overnight?
All right.
I know I'm going to regret this, but what the hell?
Oh, dear.
But I just said I know I'm going to regret this.
All right.
You wake up in the morning and find inside of your room
a harper agent?
No, the Zentarum.
Come on.
The Zentarim.
No.
You find a letter addressed to you.
Who?
To Vukrad.
Fukradin.
Oh, I find a letter addressed to me.
Yes.
Oh, dear.
Do you read it?
I shared it with every.
I'm reading it.
Should I not be reading it?
I'm assuming.
Is it from a fan?
Is it a fan letter?
You should read it all.
From a friend to True Justice.
I'm hoping it's a fan letter.
I've never gotten a fan letter.
It is a fan letter in a very roundabout way.
Oh, well, then I'll definitely want to read it.
Oh, my God.
Markaster's back.
Wait, how smart gaster?
Yeah.
Oh, my goodness.
Oh, those guys.
Have a fan.
Everybody's evil.
Well, like I said, I wasn't sure that I fully trusted them.
I did say that just about five minutes ago.
Yes.
So you did.
I am being more cautious.
I'm not wearing the pin.
The pin is gone.
Okay.
Lost in battle.
That's fine.
I just want to make sure you did get the note.
Yes.
Okay.
Can I cast identify on the note?
It's not magical.
It only has to be.
There's another girl gone.
Yes.
You read the rules.
There's like, I think there's a spell called Legend and Lore.
I think that's the one you're looking for.
That's really high level, isn't it?
I don't know.
Legend and Lore.
Level five spell.
It's a level five spell.
Yeah, it's pretty far away.
Yeah.
And it's something famous.
It's only for things that are famous.
Well, it's really for whatever the GM wants to be bothered to create lore for, so the GM doesn't get hammered by players casting legendary drink it.
Just so we're on the same page.
The real balance, the real game balance, yeah.
Just to be clear, as a GM, yeah, you don't need to do spell components.
No, no, but for that spell.
Oh, yeah.
How many pearls do you have?
You don't have any pearls.
Oh, wait, you have six?
I gave you six pearls.
Why was I thinking?
Make the die roll for him.
Wait, I thought you cached those pearls just the other day.
Nope.
No, we got them in the lighthouse.
I was just joking that usually Gary, first thing they do, you go to a town and Gary converts everything in immediately.
We even said that when we walked into town, like, can we sell this treasure?
And I was like, no.
We can't do that with Ukraine in the mix.
Like, we got to, like, I don't know, do a BA Barakas on him or something to sell our treasure.
Here, drink this milk, you know.
All right.
Some warm tea.
Okay.
So, morning.
So you got the note in the morning.
All right.
It was from the Harpers.
That was the only event during the rest cycle.
Okay.
That was the only.
I think after hearing about the Harpers and now getting this note, I think I'm interested in connecting with them.
Who?
The Harpers.
Okay.
Do you declare that publicly?
No, I think we're.
The days of public declaration is over.
Okay.
Do we all have an uncommon language we all speak so we can have our discussions?
No, I'm assuming if you're not shouting, if you're not shouting in.
We're in our bedroom, right?
We just woke up and there was a note here.
Yeah, we all share a bedroom.
My investigation was, you know, like, does it seem like there's some way that they got in, you know, like scuff marks?
No, no, it's just slid under the door, I assume.
Sure.
Slid under the door.
Oh, okay.
Right.
I guess we could ask the tavern master if there were any unusual visitors last night.
Anyone out of the ordinary?
Come through.
He looks at you.
Did you just come upstairs and not stay?
No.
He goes, why do you ask?
I just thought I heard something last night.
Oh, no, no, nothing.
Nothing.
Then he turns to you.
Oh, but by the way, did you get the note?
Oh, it was a Spider-Man.
Where did the note come from?
The note came from Neverwinter.
I was told to give it to you.
Oh, you were the middleman.
Okay.
Who gave it to you?
It came with the post.
Oh.
Neverwinter knows we're here.
How are we on Neverwinter's radar?
No, because we took the jobs.
We took the job in Neverwinter.
Oh, yeah.
I suppose it came in the post.
Okay.
Shadows?
What?
How many letters were there?
Well, I was just given this one.
Oh.
Are you giving it to us right now?
No, he gave that.
It's the letter.
It's the letter he put it.
I put it underneath your door.
He's the one who slid it under the door.
And you said it came from Neverwinter.
Yes.
I don't ask where somebody's somebody some of these notes come from.
I'm a gentleman.
I don't sit there and pry and say, who is it from?
What was the purpose of the letter?
Why was it sent?
I was presented with this, and I gave it.
Makes sense.
It was a private letter.
So thank you for delivering that.
I forgot to give it to you last night.
Have a silver piece.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
I forgot to give it to you last night.
That's all.
All right.
What's next, folks?
Next is, we're out of time.
So.
Whispering Woods.
Whispering Woods?
I'm going to say Soma had trouble sleeping with Soma wants to take on the Whispering Woods.
After Adabra's mention of it and all, yeah.
Well, you know, we're friends.
I can back you up on that.
All right.
And maybe that's where the carver is.
I have my doubts.
Me too.
All right.
I don't think you're going to come back with any money.
You're going to come back with a happier guide.
Yes, that is true.
That is a happy guide, it is a safer guide.
Well, the more of these organizations we can get on our side, probably the better for us.
It's going to, we're going to, you know.
We can be allies with all of them until they find out that we're allies with their enemies.
They're not enemies.
I just want to be careful.
They have differences of opinion.
Just to be clear, in my campaigns, because I can't be bothered to, factions have factions.
Not everybody within an organization agrees with everybody else.
They have ambitions and goals and whatnot.
Just keep that in mind.
They're not, you know.
Sir Kalen is not every member of the Order of the Gauntlet.
Yes, and doesn't necessarily agree with everybody in the Order of the Gauntlet.
And you might meet other members of the Order of the Gauntlet who might have a very different perspective than he does.
Oh, you said factions have factions.
I heard like actions have factions.
I'm like, that made no sense.
Factions have factions.
Yes.
They're not.
There's a schism every other day.
I gotcha.
Right.
And the more blinkered you are, the more likely, you know, the more pure, the more purist you are, the more.
Well, I figure the bigger you are, right?
The bigger the org.
So I was having a bit.
Well, you know, it's kind of like, you know, the more purist you are, the more likely you are to have factions.
So the Order of the Gauntlet, for example, and the Emerald Enclave are more liable to factions than the Harpers and the Zentarim, who are motivated.
Well, the Zentarim is very, they have factions because, well, they're a bunch of cutthroats.
Well, they're all good as what stab each other in the back.
Yeah, their Game of Thrones, the most unbelievable group of, you know.
Yeah, but they've got their factions are at least for rational reasons, accumulation of power and wealth.
Yeah.
Right.
I don't see myself allying the Zentarum.
Yes, you know, the Lord of the Lord's Alliance also has factions because, yes, we're all parts of the Lord's Alliance, but everybody's trying to conquer everybody else.
Right.
And they're all trying to grow their realms.
And there's always the seer in the background keeping the balance.
All right.
All right, man.
Good night.
Hope you guys have fun.
Had a good one.